NAVEED RAMZAN

Cell: +92-332-629-1518

E-mail: nramzan19@yahoo.com **PEC Number:** ELECT/52884

Date of birth: 27 Feb 1992

Address: Street # 3 House 34J Near Model Colony Firdous Market Lahore, Pakistan

SUMMARY-

Passionate and hardworking RF Engineer with more than 4 years' experience as DT Engineer, Post Processor and coordinator. I am active team player with excellent communication and customer orientation skills. Looking for a challenging career opportunity in a multinational or regional organization in the fields of Electrical telecom engineering, RF planning, Optimization and Network operations & maintenance. Where my background, education, skills and creativity can be utilized to add value addition to the company.

EXPERIENCE-

Sublime Wireless International

RF Engineer (April 2017 to Date)

I have joined Sublime Wireless Innovations Lahore from April 2017 as RF Engineer on Nokia USA TMO Project.

Responsibilities in SWI:

- RF coordination with Drive test engineers, live support to DT engineers. Responsible for resolving issues related to drive test, like band locking, sites access, different layers and sectors testing, SSV, Swap testing, Cluster testing.
- Responsible for work order of given sites for drive testing. Uploading WO on remote server. Report
 generation of different layers and post processing of logs & report submission on server and to
 Nokia official.
- Responsible for EFDS tracker of drive test and tester and keeping record of bonus sheets of DTE.
- Uploading TEMS logfiles on Actix server remotely. Site assignment to DTE on portal. And handling issue with error sites. Cluster Reports processing on Actix analyzer/MapInfo and Nemo Analyzer.
- Responsible for whole coordination in Houston, Kansas, Oklahoma & Puerto Rico Markets, billing sheet of these markets, inventory management, Drive test team's management according to work load, training new DTE and giving them live support.
- Responsible for 4.75G testing like LAA testing and NB_IoT and MIMO testing and reporting.
 Extracting data from Nokia remote server for sites status check and maintaining KPI's of assigned Markets.

LCC Pakistan

RF Engineer Level III

(Oct 2015 to Apr 2017)

I have joined LCC Pakistan from October 2015 as RF Engineer working on Jazz Benchmarking Project in RF planning and optimization department.

Responsibilities in LCC:

- Performed city level drive testing using Nemo Invex II, Nemo Outdoor & TEMS Investigation.
- Analysis of logfiles using Nemo Analyzer and Report generation.
- Drive testing for coverage, Audio Quality MOS, Call setup and success rates, Handovers, Drop call and FTP throughput rates for 2G/3G/4G<E.
- Monitoring parameters of Rx Level, Rx Quality, RSCP, Ec/No, RSRP, RSRQ, SQI, SNR, HTTP Throughput DL & UL Rates, etc.
- DT KPIs and Layer 3 signaling messages analysis for Accessibility, Retainability and Mobility.
- Responsible for preparation of Executive City level 4G/3G/2G Benchmarking reports for comparison of Jazz with three other networks for the different Cities.

- Customer complaints handling from issue based on Walk tests of customer complaints to improve the RF condition to solution purposed.
- PTA city level testing, Sites Audits, Cluster Acceptance testing and post processing with Nemo Tools.
- Responsible for initial optimization for changing Antenna Tilt and sector swapped correction for best results.
- RF Access Statistic monitoring on Huawei M2000/U2000/PRS and escalation of degradation in KPIs or hardware failures.
- Frequency planning for new sites in Map Info software. MBU's testing and their Optimization.

SayBi

DT & Analysis Engineer

(Dec 2014 to August 2015)

I am attached with SayBi from December 2014 as Drive Test and Analysis Engineer in Mobilink Drive test and Reporting Project in QoS department.

Responsibilities in Mobilink:

- Performed Drive testing to analyze and Benchmark Network Performance. Proficient with drivetesting tools such as NemoInvex-I, Nemo Outdoor & TEMS Investigation.
- Planned drive test routes, carried out testing for Coverage, Audio Quality MOS (using PSEQ & POLQA), Call Setup and Success rates, Handovers and FTP throughput rates for GSM/GPRS/EDGE/WCDMA/HSPA/LTE services.
- Post processing and analysis of Log files using Nemo Analyzer, TEMS& MapInfo.
- Analysis of Drop calls, Call setup failures, Inter/Intra Frequency Handover failures using Layer 3
 Signaling Messages in Nemo Analyzer.
- Prepared Executive City level 4G/3G/2G Benchmarking reports for comparison of Mobilink with three other networks for the different Cities.
- Data extraction from IManager2000 using quires and to record data for BSC level for daily network monitoring.
- Testing using different Apps for coverage and Quality like MCC, TEMS Mobile Insight, Qmon and Coverage View.

EDUCATION-

Bachelor in Electrical (Telecomm) Engineering NUST, Military College of Signals, Rawalpindi

(2010 - 2014)

(CGPA 3.01/4.0)

SKILLS

MS Office Tools

TEMS Investigation

DJSU testing

Map Info Professional

Nemo Analyzer

AirView

- AnyDesk
- Nemo Invex/Outdoor
- PRS Client 106
- IManager2000
- Atoll
- Actix

WORKSHOPS-

- Attended workshop on 3G Cellular Systems: Technical Overview, Planning and Optimization from HEC at Military college of Signals in 2014.
- Attended workshop Voyage of Telecommunication Industry A look on 2.5G/3G/4G from Brain Beret at Military College of Signals in 2014.

REFFERENC-

It will be furnished on Demand.